MOHAMED ZOUARI

Software Engineer | AWS Certified Developer

SUMMARY

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with experience, working effectively in a dynamic multi-national enterprise environment. An AWS Certified Developer. I am currently trying to reshape some Cloud Software Development experiences, contributing to designing, maintaining, testing and implementing large-scale and distributed cloud-based projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, C/C++.

Cloud Providers: AWS.

Databases: SQL, MongoDB, PostgresQL, Oracle.

Operating Systems: Unix/Linux, Windows.

Automation Tools: Terraform, Jenkins, SaltStack, Ansible, Vagrant, Gitlab CI/CD

Software Design & Methodologies: Web Services, REST, MVC, MVP, Testing, Agile, KANBAN, SCRUM, TDD.

EXPERIENCE

SAP Jul 2022 – Present

Software Development Engineer

<u>Infor</u> Sep 2020 – Jul 2022

Software Development Engineer

- Contributed to the design and the implementation of a (Python) CLI utility to manage and generate automatically the deployment workflows as a layer on top of an internal deployment tool:
 - Designed the new concept of workflow as collection of deployments and test actions associated with a specific AWS deployment environment.
 - Implemented the CLI generation tool to use generic config files to create workflows in a customizable way.
 - Added package process using a GitLab CI, to build and publish the project built artifact to an AWS S3 bucket.
 - Created an update feature to get the latest shared version from the S3 bucket and promote it from CLI.
 - Results: Improved the lifecycle of all the deployed products. The team reached a more efficient working cycle.
- Contributed in the enhancement and the creation of new features for internal platform that manages cloud environments :
 - Updated the API layer (Python Pyramid) and the task processing side (Celery, RabbitMQ, SQLAlchemy).
- Designed and Implemented the automation to deploy a new multi-tier project on a cloud-based infrastructure on top of the internal deployment tool:
 - Implemented SaltStack scripts to fully configure the remotely created compute nodes (CloudFormation).
- Reduced the deployment time by updating the used environments and automations :
 - Packaged the API codebase and the UI code and added the package process using a GitLab CI.
 - Enhanced the automation (Salt) scripts to configure the freshly created cloud compute nodes (EC2 nodes).
 - Results: Reduced the deployment time by 40%.
- Designed a new release of an internal platform for a multi-environment support and cross-account availability:
 - Designed and implemented an integration environment, refreshed from CI pipeline stages to redeploy the application servers and trigger a lambda function that refreshes the load balancer target groups.
 - Designed and implemented a temporary feature testing environment to enable developer testing newly implemented features from a code branch.
 - Exposed the platform via a custom endpoint service and AWS PrivateLink to other VPCs in external accounts.
 - Results: Reduced the deployment time by 100% (Fully automated), and enabled cross accounts access.

Integration Objects Feb 2020 – Jul 2020

Software Development Engineering Intern

- Designed and implemented a monitoring module for a distributed and large-scale industrial IoT platform:
 - Implemented a microservice to collect and manage remote exposed metrics, data, using scheduled jobs.

Lemhaf

Mar 2021 - Currently Maintaining

The first Tunisian services sharing online platform

- Created a full-stack web platform, to allow users find out services they need and to allow service providers to connect with the community :
 - Designed, and implemented a three-tier architecture for a cross-platform online sharing website.
 - Implemented a responsive front-end UI (ReactJS, Ant Design, Material Design).
 - Deployed a back-end server (NodeJS, ExpressJs), connected with a non relational database (MongoDB).
 - Used a distributed storage cloud solution to host media files.
 - Implemented an authentication and authorization component with email verification.
 - Results: Actually Running, with (860 users, and 1540 shared services).
 - Actually working on an upgrade by adding a service recommendation engine based on services rating and user previous activities..

EagleEye | Github Repo | Demo

April 2019

A real-time reputation monitoring platform

- Designed and implemented a real time solution for reputation tracking and monitoring on (Twitter):
 - o Implemented some back-end microservices using (Spring Cloud).
 - o Implemented a sentiment analysis microservice (Python).
 - o Implemented a stream processing module using Kafka as a message broker.
 - o Integrated Elasticsearch to process the streams for real time monitoring on a dashboard (Kibana).
 - **Results:** Deployed the platform on AWS and tested it 3h before Tunisian Presidential Election results announcements to get a comparison of the reputation of the two candidates near the real results.

EDUCATION

National Engineering School of Tunis, Tunis, Tunisia

Sep 2017 - Jul 2020

M.Eng.CS, Software Engineering

Computer Science engineering degree with a major in Software Engineering.

Paris Descartes University, Paris, France

Sep 2019 - Oct 2020

M.Res, Computer Science

Master of research degree M2, Computer Science with a major in Signal Processing.

Preparatory Institute El Manar, Tunis, Tunisia

Sep 2015 - Jun 2017

B.Sc, Mathematics and Physics

Ranked among the top 5% nationwide in the national exam.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

Credentials

Dec 2021 - Dec 2024

Google IT Automation Professional Certificate Credentials

Oct 2020 - No Exp

EXTERNAL ACTIVITIES

Active Member

ENIT Arts club

IEEE

Sep 2017 - Present

Sep 2017 - 2020

Chairman of the board, Violinist

Chairman of the board, violinist

• Led a music band of engineering students as the violinist of the group, to participate in national musical events.